Guide to the Louise Hortense Branscomb Papers, 1864-2002 and undated RL.00145
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Bound Volumes, 1880s-1990s
  - Medical Notebooks
    - Obstetrics/Gynocology, Woman's Hospital, 1928-1929 (Box 10)
    - Record of Operations at Franklin Square Hospital, 1930-1931 (Box 10)
    - Tropical Medicine, Army Medical Center, Washington, DC, 1944 (Box 10)
- Photographs, 1890s-1990s
  - First Ramsey Class Banquet, Birmingham, 1909 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous family portraits and formal photographs, undated (Box 11)
  - United Nations work in Greece, 1945 and undated (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1940s-1980s (Box 11)
  - Identification cards and membership cards, 1920s-1990s (Box 11)
  - Portraits of L.H. Branscomb, 1920s-1980s (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous family snapshots, undated; 3 folders (Box 11)
- Family History, 1860s-1980s
  - Alabama Christian Advocate, 1930 Sept. (Box 9)
  - Coin purse, undated (Box 9)
  - Genealogies and obituaries, undated (Box 11)
  - Confederate money and IOUs, 1860s-1900s (Box 11)
  - First United Methodist Church, Birmingham, 1940s-1990s (Box 11)
  - L.C. Branscomb, Southern University, 1884-1886 (Box 11)
  - L.C. Branscomb writings, 1890s-1920s (Box 11)
  - Clippings re: L.C. Branscomb, 1920s-1960s (Box 11)
  - L.C. Branscomb memorial book, 1930 (Box 11)
  - L.C. Branscomb memorials, 1940s-1950s (Box 11)
  - Flower arrangement cards from L.C. Branscomb's funeral, 1930 (Box 11)
  - L.C. Branscomb and Minnie McGehee marriage, 1900 Jun. 5 (Box 11)
  - Minne McGehee, Epworth League, 1899 (Box 11)
  - Clippings re: Minnie McGehee Branscomb, 1950s and undated (Box 11)
  - Clippings collected by Minnie Branscomb, 1960s and undated (Box 11)
  - Minnie McGehee Branscomb, Children's Home Board of Directors, 1950s-1960s (Box 11)
  - Minnie McGehee Branscomb, Fair Haven Methodist Home for Aging, 1959-1960s (Box 11)
  - Condolences, funeral for Minnie McGehee Branscomb, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Lewis Branscomb, 1901-1912 (Box 11)
  - Harvie Branscomb, 1920s-1985 (Box 11)
  - Alline Branscomb, undated (Box 11)
  - Richard Edwin Branscomb, 1980 and undated (Box 11)
  - Elizabeth Branscomb's baby hair, undated (Box 11)
  - Lamar Branscomb, 1940s-1956 (Box 11)
  - Emily Branscomb, 1918 and undated (Box 11)
  - Nannie McAdory Branscomb, 1890s (Box 11)
  - Elizabeth Murrell Branscomb, 1906 (Box 11)
  - Mrs. J.L. McGehee, undated (Box 11)
- Correspondence, 1870s-1990s
  - Correspondence, 1870s-1890s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1900s (Box 13)
  - Courtship letters from L.C. Branscomb to Minnie McGehee, 1899-1900 (Box 13)
  - L.C. Branscomb to Minnie McGehee Branscomb, 1900-1912 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1910s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1920s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1930s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence re: L.C. Branscomb's accident and death, 1930 Sept.-Nov.; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1940s; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1950s (Box 13)
  - Elizabeth Branscomb to Robert M. Cochran, 1955-1956 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 13)
- Personal Papers, 1901-1999
  - Baby book, 1901 and undated (Box 12)
  - UN Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1945-1946 (Box 12)
  - Huntingdon College, 1950-1993 (Box 12)
  - Birmingham medical practice, 1940s and undated (Box 12)
  - Travel to Korea, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - Travel to Korea, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Travel to China: speech notes, article, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
  - Speeches: Church-related, 1967-1986 (Box 12)
  - Speeches: Laity Day, 1973-1983 (Box 12)
  - Speeches: Political/Equal Rights Amendment, 1973-1976 (Box 12)
  - Speeches: Medical, 1974-1977 (Box 12)
  - Speeches: Miscellaneous, 1970s-1980s (Box 12)
  - Research/medical journal articles, 1948-1960 (Box 12)
  - Clippings with published writings, 1947-1986 (Box 12)
  - Clippings re: L.H. Branscomb, 1920s-1990s; 7 folders (Box 12)
  - Johns Hopkins reunion, 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Housing Authority of Birmingham District, 1970s-1980s (Box 12)
  - 100 Women in Mission, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Wesleyan Service Guild, other Methodist Church ephemera, 1950s-1970s (Box 12)
  - Birmingham Southern College Branscomb Collection, 1980s (Box 12)
  - Birmingham Southern College scholarships, 1990s (Box 12)
  - Notes and dictionary, 1967, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Southern Women's Archives, 1979 (Box 12)
  - 90th Birthday, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Research paper re: L.H. Branscomb written by Anne Mitchell, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Address books, etc., undated (Box 12)
  - Notes re: travel, trips, etc., undated (Box 12)
  - Sale of house, Birmingham, 1992-1993 (Box 12)
  - Kirkwood by the River, 1990s (Box 12)
  - Resume/CV, 1950s-1990s (Box 12)
  - Awards/certificates, 1949-1980s (Box 12)
  - Diplomas and certificates, 1921-1931 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Clippings saved by L.H. Branscomb, undated (Box 12)
  - Vital and legal records (incl. will, Power of Attorney), 1966-1990s (Box 12)
  - Obituaries/funeral/memorials, 1999 (Box 12)